<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello!</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Salary Survey in Poland 2019</title>
      <link>/2020/02/03/data-science-salary-survey-in-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/03/data-science-salary-survey-in-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>What is a Data Science Salary Survey?At the end of 2019 as one of the Warsaw R Enthusiasts Meetup initiatives I designed a salary survey for broadly understood data science/data analysis/machine learning job market in Poland. This exercise was inspired by the similar survey from Germany. A survey was advertised using social media among the R/data science/machine learning community. Despite Meetup organizers’ attempts to reach as many people in the community as possible, I acknowledge that these results don’t represent everyone on the Polish data science scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parental leave across OECD countries</title>
      <link>/2019/05/03/parental-leave-across-oecd-countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/03/parental-leave-across-oecd-countries/</guid>
      <description>A quick look into paid leave available to momsI was recently researching maternity leave options in Poland. In simplification as a mother in Poland you can get:
a year of a paid leave at a rate 80% (20 weeks of maternity leave and 32 of parental leave)half a year (20 weeks maternity leave + 6 weeks parental leave) paid 100% and another half 60% (26 weeks of parental leave).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trendiest baby names in Poland</title>
      <link>/2019/04/10/the-trendiest-baby-names-in-poland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/10/the-trendiest-baby-names-in-poland/</guid>
      <description>It is a challenge to choose a name for your baby. At least it has been for me. To make this decision easier I wanted to look into current trends, as neither my husband nor I wanted a baby to have a super popular name. If you want to know what names are currently trending in Poland this post is for you.
Polish Ministry of Digitalization publishes the baby names statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Olga Mierzwa-Sulima and I am a Senior Data Scientist at Appsilon. I love solving problems using data, beautiful visualizations, dogs and back-country skiing.
I hold a Master degree in Econometrics from the University of Rotterdam in the Netherlands. I have been working for boutique consulting companies helping global clients, like Unilever, NN or WHO. I&amp;rsquo;m huge enthusiast of the statistical programming language R, which is my primary tool at work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>