<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Hello!</title>
    <link>/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Hello!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Tackling Climate Change useR! 2020 breakout session</title>
      <link>/2020/07/12/recap-tackling-climate-change-user-2020-breakout-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/12/recap-tackling-climate-change-user-2020-breakout-session/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, July 7th I organized a breakout session Tackling Climate Change at a virtual useR!2020 Munich.When I submitted the proposal I hoped the session will be a mix of an invited talk, climate-related contributions submitted to the useR! and an open discussionbetween R users and researchers. In an online setup, the final session schedule was a bit different.
The session lasted almost 2 scheduled hours. Around 130 people joined the session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Salary Survey in Poland 2019</title>
      <link>/2020/02/03/data-science-salary-survey-in-poland-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/03/data-science-salary-survey-in-poland-2019/</guid>
      <description>What is a Data Science Salary Survey?At the end of 2019 as one of the Warsaw R Enthusiasts Meetup initiatives I designed a salary survey for broadly understood data science/data analysis/machine learning job market in Poland. This exercise was inspired by the similar survey from Germany. A survey was advertised using social media among the R/data science/machine learning community. Despite Meetup organizers’ attempts to reach as many people in the community as possible, I acknowledge that these results don’t represent everyone on the Polish data science scene.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>